this problem asks us to
write a program that prints a greeting
message
and we're going to do this by defining a
method called greeting
with a parameter called name
in our method definition we'll write out
a greeting
and we'll use concatenation to
include the user's name as part of our
greeting
the problem description tells us
specifically that our greeting method
should return a string the return value
of a method
is the evaluated result of the last line
executed
our greeting method has only one line
and on that line
is a string which will be the return
value
of this method now you may think that
because we want our program to print
this greeting we should
output this string from within the
method on line two by invoking put s
however the return value of invoking the
put s method is
nil because line two is the last line
executed within our greeting
method invoking put us on line 2 would
cause our greeting method to return nil
we can demonstrate the return value of
invoking put us
in irb so i'll call put us
and pass it the string hello and we
expect that this will
output the string hello but return nil
and that's what we see
so if the last line executed within our
method
is an invocation of put us our methods
return value will be nil
so in order to adhere to the problem
requirements and return the string from
our method
we'll remove that call to put s instead
we'll output the greeting when we invoke
the greeting method
so on line five we can invoke our
greeting method we'll pass it the name
bob
in order to output this string we can
call put us on line five
the return value of our greeting method
will be passed as the argument to put
us an output to the screen let's run our
code and see that
our file is called exercise.rb
when i run it in the terminal we see our
greeting string
always remain aware of the return value
of your methods
and remember that put s returns nil